RESUME



KERRY CHIN CPA (Australia), CAMS, CA (Singapore) 陈可俐

Age : 28 years old

Nationality : Malaysian, Singapore Permanent Resident

Email : kerry.chin7@gmail.com

Address : 68 Lor G, Telok Kurau, 04-08 The Medley, 426258 Singapore.

Mobile : +6590709923

Languages : Fluent in English, Mandarin, Cantonese & Bahasa Melayu.

Able to speak fundamental Japanese.

Hobbies : Passionate about cooking, sports and scuba diving.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:

University of South Australia, Adelaide, Australia.

2007 — 2009 Bachelor of Commerce

Major in Professional Accounting & Finance, CGPA 5.5/7, Distinction

Foon Yew High School 宽柔中学, Johor Bahru, Malaysia

2005 — 2006 Tertiary Foundation : Unified Examination Certificate (UEC)

2001 — 2005 Secondary Qualification: Sijil Pelajaran Malaysia (SPM)

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS:

2010 — Current CPA Australia, Certified Practising Accountant

Certificate/membership number: 9508784

2015 — Current CFA Institute, Claritas Investment Certification

Certificate/membership number: 5826

2015 — Current Institute of Singapore Chartered Accountants, Chartered Accountant

Certificate/membership number: 824596

2016 — Current Association of Certified Anti-Money Laundering Specialist, Certified Anti-

Money Laundering Specialist

Certificate/membership number: 1000232467

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES:

May 2015 — Current Sumitomo Mitsui Banking Corporation ("SMBC"), Singapore

Regional Internal Auditor, Assistant Vice President

<u>Major Achievements</u>: Notwithstanding the lack of internal audit experience prior to joining SMBC, I demonstrated my relentless desire to learn despite a steep learning curve and I was able to prove my capability by delivering quality audit work consistently. In 6 months' time, I was given the opportunity to

lead an audit team of 6 (including AVPs and VPs) as auditor-in-charge for an overseas branch of approximately 450 employees. From audit planning to audit execution, I coordinated and communicated audit request with my counterparts amicably. I applied my analytical skill to analyse and summarise voluminous financial and non-financial data into a 4-page audit planning memorandum. I also exercised professional judgment with supporting data to determine the scope of the audit which I presented it to the regional head of Asia Pacific directly for approval. I managed the audit execution and communicated with branch's senior management daily to manage the expectation during the onsite audit. The audit identified a number of areas of improvement and the branch's senior management was very appreciative of the value adding recommendation as a result of the audit.

After the success of my first audit as an auditor-in-charge, I was given another opportunity to lead an audit of a wider scope with a team of 7 (including AVPs and VPs). I received positive feedbacks for the audits I led. Besides, I obtained a new qualification in 2016 as a Certified Anti-Money Laundering Specialist to further enhance my knowledge and hone my skill especially in the area of AML/CTF.

<u>Areas of audit covered</u>: Front office (corporate banking departments, wealth management department, cash management service – electronic banking), back office operations (deposits, remittances, cash banking, trade finance, customer instructions such as opening, closing account and reactivating dormant account), legal and compliance, AML audit (framework, KYC onboarding, KYC ongoing monitoring, transaction filtering and screening, transaction monitoring), support groups audit (human resource, learning and development, budget and expense, outsourcing and service provider)

My essential duties as an internal auditor and an auditor-in-charge include but not limited to:

- Lead audit team as auditor in charge from audit planning, execution and audit reporting.
- Verbally communicate findings to senior management, draft comprehensive recommendation and issue audit opinion via a detailed root cause analysis.
- Present audit result to the country's regulator via face-to-face meeting and address query from regulator.
- Document auditable process and conduct follow up audits or meeting to monitor management's remediation action plan status.
- Engage to continuous knowledge development regarding Asia Pacific countries regulations and summarise the relevant updates to incorporate the necessary coverage into audit.
- Conduct yearly risk assessment and quarterly continuous monitoring of assigned Asia Pacific countries.
- Extensive exposure to Know Your Client and Anti Money Laundering theme audits in Asia Pacific countries.
- Establish risk-based audit programs and determine scope of review in conjunction with the audit partner and regional head.
- Review the suitability of internal control design and conduct audit testing of to identify reportable issues and dimension of risk.
- Evaluate compliance with policies and procedures of the bank and country regulations.
- Conduct quality assurance assignments and advisory engagement.

Mar 2014 — May 2015 Franklin Templeton Investments, Singapore

Senior Fund Analyst

- Conducted risk-based review of Net Asset Value (NAV) reporting for Asia Pacific and Cayman funds and provide guidance to the operation groups and direct report to Manager.
- Coordinated with internal and external auditors periodically for audit and financial reporting.
- Worked closely with Compliance to resolve regulator's queries over the funds.
- Responsible for answering queries of complex accounting issues occurring within the products and manage client expectations and partnering with other business units effectively for prompt issue resolution.
- Monitored performance against the service level agreements established with internal clients (cash
 accounting team, treasury accounting team, sales, compliance, trading desk) as well as external
 clients (outsource service providers, custodian, trustee) and documented the evaluation in report
 format on a regular basis.
- Participated in fund launches and projects to support project objective, address concern and implement project strategies.
- Reviewed monthly reports produced by operations team for accuracy and reasonableness.
- Reviewed expense ratio analysis and funds payments for accuracy and reasonableness.
- Reviewed quarterly, semi-annual, annual financial statements and other local regulatory and trustee reporting.
- Reviewed department procedure manual and control procedures regularly for accuracy and efficiency.

Feb 2013 — Mar 2014 PCTC Motorsport, Kuala Lumpur

Senior Accountant

- Participated in meeting with business prospects for business development which resulted in increased sales and expansion of showrooms.
- Managed sales force and promotional expenses for motor vehicles in three showrooms.
- Prepared annual reporting of financial statements and tax reporting.
- Prepared monthly account reporting which include compilation, comparison of results against budget, costing, income and expenditure analysis.

Dec 2010 — Jan 2013 PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP, Singapore

Senior Associate Year 2 – Financial Services (High Performance rating)

- Participated in audit of financial services institutions bank and asset management companies. My
 audit clients include Bank of America, Helios Capital Management, UT Asset Management,
 Eastspring Investments, Amundi Singapore and Seatown Holdings.
- Responsible for developing audit approach such as qualitative and quantitative analysis and
 evaluation of client's industry and business risk. For instance, evaluate management's and service
 providers' ability to maintain adequate internal control over financial reporting during periods of
 higher growth or higher complexity of their investments, investigate errors in NAV per share and
 any corrective action taken, perform audit on management's compliance with law and regulations.

- Responsible for day-to-day audit works including audit work and budget planning, control testing, substantive audit works, coaching and supervising junior associates, reporting to manager-incharge and partner-in-charge.
- Responsible for reviewing draft financial statements, preparing audit finding report and communicating audit findings to manager-in-charge, partner-in-charge and client's management, able to establish and retain effective working relationship with both the team and the client.
- Led audit engagement team of five team members and completed audit within scheduled reporting timeline.

Dec 2009 — Dec 2010 **Deloitte & Touche LLP, Singapore**

Audit Associate (High Performance rating)

- Participated in audit engagements of private and public listed companies in diverse industries which include Real Estate, Manufacturing, Consumer Retail Business, Shipping and Food and Beverage. (i.e. Cheung Kong Holdings, Rockwell Automation, TRS Singapore-Prada, Hartmann Asia, Fitness First, Tung Lok Group)
- Completed audit works for various sections of financial statement which include cash, investment, account receivable, account payable, accruals, debts, tax, sales, cost of sales and expenses with minimal supervision and support from audit senior.

Dec 2008 — Feb 2009 KPMG, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Audit Internship Trainee

• Assisted in completing financial audit fieldwork in manufacturing and real estate industries which includes testing of control, transactions and balances.

PERSONAL SKILLS:

- Amicable interpersonal skills and ability to communicate effectively (multilingual).
- Comprehensive problem solving skill and multitasking ability.
- A fast learner and self starter with the desire to excel.
- Able to meet tight deadlines with excellent time management.
- Self defined and adaptable to different working conditions.
- Good at working in groups yet able to work individually.
- Proficient in common PC, Microsoft Office and Lotus Notes applications.

ACTIVITIES & LEADERSHIP SKILLS:

2010 —2013 PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP, Singapore

 Participate in various corporate responsibility activities which include PwC FSIP Gives Back at Marina Gardens by the Bay with clients from Sundac, annual JP Morgan Chase Challenges and SGX Bull Charge Charity Marathon.

2008 —2009 CPA Australia Student Charter, CPA

Committee Member

• Active in organising accounting-related events and seminars.

2007 —2009 Business School Accounting Club, University of South Australia

Committee member

• Active in organising accounting-related events and club activities.

2000 —2005 Associated Board of the Royal Schools of Music, United Kingdom Participant

• Accomplish six years of piano lessons and took piano practical and theory examinations consistently. Keen to accept challenges and achieve progressive target.

ACADEMIC AWARDS:

NAME AND YEAR OF AWARDS:	SPONSOR'S NAME
University Merit Awards 2009	University of South Australia, Adelaide
University Merit Awards 2008	University of South Australia, Adelaide
University Merit Awards 2007	University of South Australia, Adelaide
TUC-UEC Scholarship 2007	Taylor's University